Yueun Kim

★ yueunkim.dev in yueunk yueunk Denver, CO yk@yueunkim.dev

Summary

I am a full-stack software engineer with a passion for collaborating to solve challenging problems. I have experience with the JavaScript, Ruby, and Go ecosystems. Most recently, I created Cascade ②, an open-source containerized application deployment solution with automated observability built with Node.js/Express, OpenTelemetry, React, and Terraform CDK for TypeScript.

Experience

2022 – present

Creator, Software Engineer

Cascade (https://try-cascade.github.io □)

- Prototyped and built Cascade, an open-source containerized application deployment solution with support for observability
- Streamlined the build and teardown processes of AWS infrastructure creation using Terraform CDK for TypeScript
- Published an NPM package for tracing instrumentation compatible with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry Collector and AWS X-Ray
- Constructed an API server for communication with the AWS SDK
- Designed a GUI for visualization of resource creation statuses real-time via SSE
- Automated installation of Cascade using Docker (images, docker-compose)
- Authored a comprehensive technical case study on design decisions and challenges of building Cascade
- Collaborated with a remote team of 4 engineers across 3 timezones using agile workflow

2020 - 2022

Full-Stack Web Developer

Developed open-source software using Ruby, Node.js, Express, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, HTML/CSS, and more

- Selected projects:
 - Yarn Basket: a real-time webhook debugging tool with custom endpoints (Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, DigitalOcean Droplet, Nginx, PM2)
 - The Shoppe: a database-backed e-commerce app (Node, React, MongoDB, Docker)
 - Flight Tracker: an SVG map for filtering and viewing airline routes (React, Docker)

2014 - 2020

Director of Piano Performance

Vivaldi Music Academy

- Crafted curricula for the piano department, and trained piano instructors
- Conducted masterclasses, workshops, and private lessons to students
- Toured with faculty and student performers contributing to the highest growth rate in academy history expanding from one to four locations in the Greater Houston area

Skills

Backend

Node.js, Express, Ruby, Go, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful APIs

Frontend

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Jest, HTML/CSS, Tailwind CSS

Tooling

Git/GitHub, Docker, Linux, Bash, OpenTelemetry, AWS (S3, SQS, EC2, ECS), Terraform

Education

Rice University, Master of Music, Piano Chamber Music

Northwestern University, Master of Music, Piano Performance and Pedagogy

Eastman School of Music, Bachelor of Music, Piano Performance